La Elaha Ella Allah (There is no god but One God)
Alhamdu Lillah, Wa Ash-hadu Alla Elaha Ella Allah Wahdahu La Shareeka Lah.
We praise God and we bear witness there is only One God.
God is doing everything.
And this is the conclusion that we must reach
if we are to be saved.
That God is doing everything is a quality of God.
If you don't know this quality, then you don't know God.
And this is why the Quran is full of those verses
talking about people who do believe in God
but they're going to Hell
because they do not know God as He really is.
In Sura 8, verse 17,
we're told that God...
There was the appearance of a battle
with a small handful of believers fighting a big huge army of disbelievers.
And the believers were busy running around and stabbing and throwing arrows and shooting, thinking they are fighting,
but the verse tells us that God is the One who's fighting; God is the One who did the killing and the throwing of the arrows.
God is doing everything.
We only do the decision to be with God or not.
And the whole design of this life is to effect a test for each one of us.
This whole life is a test,
nothing else.
And we read in Sura 51, verse 56 that God created this whole universe,
created us just to worship Him alone.
Anything else are just the means for provision,
the jobs, what you do to go to school to find work, develop your talents or whatever.
It's just an outside appearance to provide for you,
give you the dollars, the food, the roof over your head and so on.
But the main job, when you wake up in the morning, my main job today is to worship God Alone.
And to observe my duties towards God.
All those duties, of course, are designed for our own benefit to develop and grow our soul
through the prayers, the fasting and so on.
But the whole world is designed for a test
in that a person is required to pray before sunrise, for example
in order for his or her soul to grow and develop.
And some person may say oh, the sun is rising too early
4 o'clock in the morning, you know, in July and August.
They complain.
But the sunrise is at 4 o'clock, you know, I'm not gonna get up at 3:30 to do the morning prayer.
So, God says ok. I'm gonna make it rise at 7.
And God designed the earth.
It's a little bit lopsided, so it will go up and down in front of the Sun
in this way creating the winter and the short day and the long day.
And God will say ok. Now, the Sun is rising at 7 o'clock. Are you going to pray the morning prayer before sunrise?
See, God designed the test this way.
And God nullifies the excuses of everybody
in order to see who is going to make it to the Highest Heaven
and that is the person who's gonna pray before sunrise no matter what time the sun rises.
And also to assure the place of those who are going to the
lowest pit of Hell
because even when the sun rises at 7 o'clock, they will not pray the morning before sunrise.
So, you can see the range of the time of sunrise and how God did it to sift out the ranks.
The people who will pray when the sun rises at 6.
And people who will pray when it rises at 6:30.
And people who do the morning prayer when it rises at a quarter of seven.
So, there'll always be dropouts.
And there will be those who pray no matter what time the sun rises.
3 in the morning, they'll be up by 2:30
and they'll do the morning prayer and go back to sleep, but they will do it.
People will say I'm gonna fast in Ramadan 16 hours? The day is 16 hours long
and I'm gonna eat no food, no water for 16 hours and it's so hot!
God says ok. I'm gonna cool it down for you. I'm gonna make it 7 hours.
And God does that.
So, you can see that the fasting days range from 7 hours, 9 hours
of cool day
to 16 hours of hot days.
And you can see the test going on
and you can see the dropouts.
Some people will fast even if the day is 20 hours in August.
And nobody dies anyway from that. It's good for you, takes down your blood pressure,
reduces your weight and all that.
And nobody dies if he or she fasts for two consecutive days.
But there are people who will fast even if the day is 20 hours long.
For the last 19 years,
we've been giving the Muslim world evidence
that they have deviated,
that we must adhere to the Quran Alone
and we've been showing them the verses in Quran.
So they said well, who is this Rashad Khalifa? He's an ignorant person
He's never been to Azhar.
And he's duping the ignorant people who don't know anything about Islam.
They wrote this.
They published it. They lectured and so on.
He's a science man. He is not a religious man.
If you hear it from a scholar,
from Azhar,
then, you can you know, they wrote that Rashad is ignorant.
He doesn't have a religious degree.
He's not from the Azhar.
And he's deceiving the ignorant people.
And God said ok, I'm gonna nullify,
like the long day, the sunrise at 7,
He said ok, I'm gonna produce for you the best Azhar scholar.
And he's sitting right with us right now. He's not a usual Azhar scholar.
He is one in a long time that was the first of his class in the freshmen, sophomore, junior and senior years.
He's not a common Azhar person.
He didn't have a connection.
A lot of people in the Azhar have connections with the dean or the president of the university and they pass and so on,
but there are special students who get this degrees and they graduate with the first honors, they call it.
And he's one of those, one of the unusual students.
And when he graduated the first of his class,
he was hired in the university
and he taught at the university
and he made his Ph.D. on the same subject that we preach here in this mosque
that the prophet will not intercede on your behalf on the day of judgement,
that the prophets are human beings who made mistakes.
And they gave him the Ph.D. with the highest degree ever in the Azhar.
So, he's not just...
God said I'm gonna give you an Azhar man, not just an Azhar man, I'm gonna give you the best.
And so, so, he goes out and he teaches and he steals the students from all the other professors.
I mean, these are facts that are recorded now in the headlines of the front pages
that came out in the last month as he was in prison
and our powerful Fãtehah got him out, ALHAMDULILLAH (Praise be to God).
But he would go and teach in the senior class
and then he will go to teach the next period, will be in the sophomore class.
The students from the senior class will follow him to the sophomore class
and the professor of the senior class will complain,
where are my kids? Where are the students?
Well, they followed Subhi Mansour to the Sophomore class.
So, he raised a lot of jealousy within the university
besides the fact that he was preaching exactly...
it's identical to what we've learned here
in this mosque and what we've been preaching.
And the enemies of Quran, the enemies of God went crazy
because God nullified their excuse.
He said ok. You don't like Rashad Khalifa who's a chemist,
Here's an Azhar man, one of your own
and one of your best.
And he is preaching the same thing.
He discovered the truth.
And I don't know where did God hide him from Satan.
You know, because Satan monopolized all those Azhar people.
He escaped somehow. God protected him.
So, he was supposed to give the KHUTBA today, but he refused. He said I wanna see your system first.
Then, I will give the KHUTBA.
Also, he wants to increase his mastership of the English language which he does very well.
You know, he really surprised me.
But we have now this newspaper saying
how did he get the Ph.D. in this subject?!
Now, they want to put his committee on trial.
Why did they give him the Ph.D.? How did that happen?
And these happen to be the leaders of the Sunna Institute.
I mean, the chairman of his Ph.D. committee is now the head of Sunna Institute in Cairo
And he says how did I do that?!
They just can't figure it out,
but he is a living proof of God's power.
They are saying let's take the Ph.D. back from him.
You know, these things are unheard of. How can you take it back?
I mean, not only have they said how did he get the Ph.D.?
How did he get the Ph.D. with this high degree, high honors, the highest honors?
They call it the first honors
مرتبة الشرف الأولى in Arabic
The rank of the highest honor.
And it had all these things and they cut it down, by the way, you know but...
After cutting out whatever they wanted, they still, they still don't like it in the newspaper.
So, this shows you the power of God and shows how God nullifies the excuses of the people in order to effect the test.
For those who don't like the sun rising at 4 o'clock, God will make it rise at 7, gradually.
And for those who don't like fasting for 16 hours in a day,
God will make it 9 hours in a cool day.
Tooboo Ela Allah. Repent.
Alhamdu Lillah, Wa Ash-hadu Alla Elaha Ella Allah Wahdahu La Shareeka Lah.
I know many of you are anxious to hear our report on our Canada trip.
One of the purposes of the KHUTBA on Friday is to study our affairs and see what is going on.
And Dr. Mansour and myself went to Canada on the weekend
and there were a number of miracles that happened.
First of all, somehow, I forgot that an Egyptian going to Canada needs a visa, an entry visa
and what is worse, an Egyptian who applies for a visa in any Canadian consulate,
they have one in Seattle,
there is a five day mandatory
mandatory five-day waiting period
because they telex Cairo and ask if this person is a terrorist or what.
And, as far as Egypt is concerned, he is the biggest terrorist in all Egypt, one could say
and his being here is actually a miracle because he is forbidden from travel.
There were people in the prison who were there for years
for religious reasons because they offended the person who was interviewing them or something.
And this is something that he did the first day.
On the first day, when they were interrogating him
the officer, or the lawyer, whoever it is, the district attorney
in the prison interviewing him and said
I'm a Muslim, I don't pray
and I don't fast, but I'm going to Heaven.
Ain't I?
He said no, you're going to Hell.
He didn't mince words.
And he is out here.
There are stories of people who offended the interrogators inside and then never made it out.
They're still there, for years.
And we know them by name,
but he is out here.
We sent a few telegrams from around the world
to the president's office in Egypt
and we read Al-Fãtehah. This is a very powerful prayer, ALHAMDU LILLAH.
So, for a variety of reasons, they let him out on his own recognizance with the stipulation that he's not to leave the country.
And now he's haunting them because we're are sending the new (Muslim) Perspective,
the title is Al-Azhar disbelieves in Quran.
Now, they called him, they called him منکر السنة (rejector of Sunna) in Egypt or
something we really admit, the rejector of Sunna.
And you know, prisons affect a person's psych somehow and
he happened to leave the prison on a miserable day. The weather, it was raining. There was mud.
Cairo was not prepared. Especially, where, the area where he lives is not prepared for rain
and there was a lot of mud there where you stepped in the mud and then you go, you leave your shoe in the mud.
put in front of you, put your foot in it
and then you leave your left shoe in the mud.
So, he caught himself talking aloud to himself saying
ok منکر السنة or rejector of Sunna,
be careful, lest you slip down or something.
So, he was out talking to himself with this title that they gave him منکر السنة (rejector of Sunna)
Now, as of the next issue of the Perspective, we're gonna call the Azhar people: منکر القرآن
The rejectors of Quran.
And we are going to issue emergency issues of the Perspective every other week
and we're mailing them to them over there.
We're proud of our title rejectors of Sunna and we'll see how proud they are with their title as rejectors of Quran.
Something that is supported by evidence
for example
an editorial, the official Azhar journal
wrote an editorial in January, the last issue
attacking him
and in that, they said that the Quran needs to be detailed.
I mean, there are about ten statements directly against Quran.
So, we're taking this statement
putting it, this is what the Azhar Ignoramuses say
and this is what God says
and we give the verses that say the Quran is fully detailed.
And we're gonna do this for the rest of the year.
Ok. We went to a ...
So, this is, I just got diverted to the miracle of him leaving Cairo, leaving Egypt.
It is an absolute miracle.
As a matter of fact, an informer in his group found out that he was leaving
but without a definite date and he did something that cancelled that informer's information.
In any rate, we're glad that he's here.
So, we headed for Canada
and Ismail Barkat, most of you know him, he's a very hot-tempered, very loud, beautiful person,
we love him,
and he was supposed to meet us in Seattle.
And he swears he was there at 1:30
and we were there at 1:00 o'clock and we waited until 3:00 o'clock.
And according to his account and our account, we existed in the same place, but we never saw each other,
We never heard each other
as loud as he is. He said...
he said I even took the public address system and I called you,
we didn't hear a thing.
We didn't see him. We didn't hear him. He didn't see us
and there was nothing.
Anyway, so, we waited until the next day
when Raymond Catton... now, Ismail went back to Seattle
and I had nothing to do, so I tried to smuggle Dr. Mansour into Canada.
It didn't work out.
I rented a car, went to the borders and usually they let you pass, you know,
because the guy at the border said where are you from? I said Tucson, Arizona.
He said can I see some IDs?
I said oh, oh, OK. So, we're gonna turn around...
So, meantime, Ismail went back to Canada
and Raymond Catton went with us in the morning to the Canadian Consulate
where we found out that we have to have five-day mandatory waiting period for an Egyptian to get a visa.
However, the vice counsel, a lady, turned out to be from Raymond Catton's old country's village,
a small village, it's called Lancashire
in England, and they spoke the same language.
You know, this is how they knew each other.
Good morning, (imitating the Lancashire dialect),
and she said good morning (imitating the response in the Lancashire dialect)
and he said oh, you're from Lancashire.
And she said that's right.
She said ok. Here's the visa.
Free.
I mean, if Ismail Barakat went with us, first we would have ended up in jail
because he's loud.
He will never go back to Vancouver without this man.
He's Dr. Mansour's best friend.
And had they mentioned that you cannot have a visa to enter Canada,
I mean, Barakat would have destroyed the Consulate,
I'm telling you, we would have ended up... thank God we just didn't see him
and he didn't see us.
So, with all these delays,
we made it to the Friday prayer in Vancouver.
And we went immediately after, after the KHUTBA
and they just finished the KHUTBA and the prayer, so we sat with them
and they all cancelled going back to work
and we sat until 4 o'clock,
from about 2 o'clock to 4 o'clock.
And we got to talk to them and
we discussed a lot of things. We did exactly everything we wanted to do
in the Friday prayer.
And then we had meetings on Friday night, Saturday night and Sunday night
in three different places
about fifty or sixty people and everything was just fantastic.
The objectors of the past didn't even show up.
There were no more objections.
And what I carried to them is the new profound conclusion that we all must have... that God is doing everything.
So, as you can tell, we'll be talking about these things for the next few weeks, IN SHAA ALLAH and
we may discuss more details tonight
and you will get a chance to greet Dr. Mansour.
We're glad, we're glad he's here.
And it is a tremendous victory.
So, it is time to quit.
Aqem Al-Salat.
Allahu Akbar. Allahu Akbar.